Muhammad Hassan Shakeel

Phone number: (+92) 3133661476 (Mobile) | Email address: mhassan20896@gmail.com | Website:

https://github.com/mHassan20896 | LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mhassan20896/ |

Whatsapp Messenger: +923441482057

ABOUT ME

Nearly 4 years experienced Software Development Engineer (SDE) with experience of developing mobile apps using Flutter in Fintech, medical and traveling domains. I am confident in the following areas of expertise:

- UI Development using Flutter
- Problem solving
- · Machine Learning
- Deep Learning
- Natural language processing
- Clean code
- Collaboration

WORK EXPERIENCE

03/2023 - CURRENT Remote, United Kingdom

SOFTWARE DEVELOPER BLOKTOPIA

- 1. Created Cryptocurrency Wallet apps for Android and iOS using Flutter.
- 2. Integrated Firebase
- 3. Integrated Web Socket API
- 4. Worked agile settings
- 5. Implemented few recommended design patterns
- 6. Wrote Unit tests
- 7. Wrote Widget tests
- 8. Remote work

06/2023 - 08/2023 Vancouver, BC, Canada

SOFTWARE ENGINEER MEADOWSVIEW CLINIC

- Implemented reCAPTCHA v3 on backend
- Developed a static website for the clinic
- Implemented a user registration form

05/2021 - 06/2023

APPLICATION DEVELOPER VENTUREDIVE

- 1. Integrated Web Socket API
- 2. Implemented animations
- 3. Worked with RESTful and GraphQL API
- 4. Implemented Watch OS Apps using SwiftUI and UIKit
- 5. Intercepted http network traffic in Flutter App for security testing
- 6. Did requirement gathering from clients
- 7. Wrote Unit tests and integration tests
- 8. Worked on medical, traveling and educational(ed-Tech) apps

01/2020 - 04/2021

APPLICATION DEVELOPER TPS WORLDWIDE

- 1. Implemented Fin-tech mobile app modules
- 2. Integrated Google Map API
- 3. Trained new software developer resources of the company

- 4. Integrated Firebase push notifications and Firebase analytics
- 5. Integrated native SDK via Method Channel

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

01/01/2016 - 31/12/2019 Karachi, Pakistan

BACHELOR'S OF COMPUTER SCIENCE University of Karachi

Field of study Computer Science

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Other language(s):

	UNDERSTANDING		SPEAKING		WRITING
	Listening	Reading	Spoken production	Spoken interaction	
ENGLISH	C1	C1	C1	C1	C1

Levels: A1 and A2: Basic user; B1 and B2: Independent user; C1 and C2: Proficient user

DIGITAL SKILLS

Software Engineering | Natural Language Processing | Deep Learning | Python | Java | Object Oriented Programming | Machine Learning | Data Structures and Algorithms | Git

Soft skills

Team management & Team work | 🖺 Effective Communication | Problem solving (problem analisys) | Initiative and proactive mindset | Collaboration and social skills

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

PROJECTS

08/2022 - 02/2023

Argo Travels Argo Travels app facilitates travellers in Brazil in getting rest house, cars for rent, to book air flight and manage their other expenses.

My role included:

- UI Development
- Problem Solving
- Collaboration with the team
- Requirement gathering from stack holders

11/2022 - 11/2022

Covid-19 India As a term project of my MS program, I did Social Network Analysis of Covid-19 spread in India. I pre-processed the raw data from <u>covid19India</u> and produced datasets of people to people contact, incoming traffic of Covid-19 patients in India and traveling pattern of Covid-19 patients in India.

I applied different techniques to devise a strategy to contain covid 19 in India, techniques included:

- Social network analysis
- Natural language processing
- Graph algorithms
- Machine learning (clustering algorithms)

I also wrote a research paper in the end as per course requirement.